hi this is a video tutorial on what we
mean we say something is transcendent or
transcendence as a category the idea
here is that we are trying to pair the
notion of transcendence with eminence
and a fractal iteration some kind of
dimensionality so those are big words
but I really want you to see that we can
get very close to some simple concepts
to understand transcendence as an
imminent property of being so if we look
at this grid here of stems we can
imagine each one of these four member
stems as being some kind of phenomenon
or a class of existence or perhaps some
kind of species and if we look at this
axis as evolutionary time then we see
that each one of these beings the ADC
b/d being the X bcz being they all have
the same evolutionary frequency or what
we might call age so this is an
ontological temporal order it happens in
time ecology of ocean as an ontology
and in this case everything started at
the same time as we've driven drawn it
and has gone on to the present if we
discounted if we took some of these out
we could see perhaps that ABCD isn't a
more recent form than the others because
they had only started at this time one
but for now I've just drawn them so that
they have the same starting point and
they come up to the future so they have
an evolutionary age of in this case for
or eons for or whatever that is in
iteration ready so that the species are
reproducing themselves over time or the
phenomenon is reoccurring over time so
that's an iteration evolutionary so what
do we mean by fractal in iteration well
we're looking for its second order
dimensionality so for example the
characteristic be iterates in a
different dimension so we can call this
depth if we want to and we see that
there are certain levels of death so i
have here 1 2 3 4 5 B has appeared five
times 1 2 3 4 5 2 has appeared two times
in this direction so we can graph it
yours to my ex appears four times SS
appears once L once and 31 so this is
can be little diagram simple diagram of
the iterative depth of these
characteristics in the evolutionary
record so we can see that this notion of
depth creates a another dimension or
another scale it dimensions or scale but
it's an abstract concept it's an
abstraction because there is no BB DVD
thing class of existence there is no to
class of existence there is no X class
of existence they never these
characteristics these abstractions never
occur by themselves there is no X there
is no be there is no 2 there's only XB s
s XB 2 3 ABCD and so there are
abstractions to another scale of
dimensions but they do iterate fractally
what i mean by fractally is that fractal
iteration means the repetition of saying
the same pneus across different scales
and so b is is repeating in this scale
you can imagine for example a bunch of
bees repeating off to this scale X is
repeating in this scale and joining with
be sometimes here sometimes joining with
SS sometimes joining with this and that
s would have depth across this scale and
so what you end up getting is this whole
fractal dimensionality of all these
aspects so this iteration and now that
you see things show up iterates
fractally across many multiple
dimensions so from the point of girth of
science we can say that if we follow
this kind of trajectory of
iterative depth then this green line
here is the kind of neat illustration of
what Goethe would call the ideal form
right so nothing actually exists there
is no creature that exists in this form
whoops so there is no creature that
exists in this form of depth 5 because
it's a matter of death but what we've
done here is uncovered an imaginary
ideal being of this class if all these
were a certain class of harm let's say
this would be the ideal that shows up as
the fractal iteration of imminent forms
so how can we talk about this further
what we can then say is that that
movement as we said in this direction is
evolution yep in this direction is depth
but when we abstract the element we look
at it as an abstract concept then we can
see that depth is associated with the
process that we called in volitional so
we get this impression when we take the
abstraction and then we create the
narrative process of how it gets in
there
see that that abstractions or
involutions of transcendence it appears
to be transcended characteristic seems
seem to be embedded or transmitted
incentive iterations they seem to be
involuted over time into these forms so
we create a pattern abstraction abstract
it from the imminent form we create the
process and think of those forms as
being out there somehow involuted into
the horns yeah so that would be then
depth associated with involution now
there's a little more to the story and
that is when this let's say creature
here xb SS develops not evolves so when
one of these creatures so we have Logan
of XP SS baby first it's just you know
let's say the dividing egg and it's
going to become a full-fledged XP SS in
this form the full characteristics of
this combination is not manifest but
these the potentials of these
combinations are involuted in the
potentials so as this form or being
arises on to genetic processes or
Joel cause a morphogenetic then we see
that there is the actual imminent
process of evolution so this is where
involution actually becomes imminent in
the ontogenetic temporalities of the
morphogenesis of the form so this is
just a little brief explanation of how
to discuss the categories of evolution
evolution transcendence and imminence in
order to see that all transcendent
categories are actually imminent and if
we can see this the stronger the
repetition so in this case B occurs five
times the stronger the repetition the
higher we see we view the transcendent
category see it as a higher transcendent
right so the stronger the repetition the
higher transcendent but when you derived
transcendence from this notion of the
fractal iteration of it immanence in a
new dimensionality then you see the
higher the transcendence also the deeper
the imminent pattern and so that would
be a host dialectical understanding of
the chemicals thanks for watching